[Music]
now how this nasty little rumor got
started that fruit makes you fat I'll
never really understand it's probably
one of two things people trying the
number one lie to you so they can sell
you something or people that just have
incomplete information they know a
little bit but not the whole story let's
unpack what's really happening here
number one the logic is fruit is made of
sugar and sugar makes you fat
therefore fruit makes you fat now both
of those statements are incorrect and
the whole summation is therefore
incorrect but why is it the cakes
number one look at the research most of
it shows that people that consume more
whole fruit actually weigh less and have
less fat we're not talking fruit snax
produces high fructose corn syrup we're
talking a whole fresh fruit so why is it
the case actually if fruit is made of
entirely sugar that people are still
then losing more weight when they're
eating a lot of whole fresh fruit a
couple of reasons number one while the
energy and fruit is mostly sugar number
one it's a special type of sugar also
number two it's actually mostly water in
this case a banana I usually like 75%
water all their fruits 80 90 about 85%
see average by the way a lot a lot of
fruit through 90 plus percent water
watermelons are like 95% water so we
have absolute volume issue
all right well stop to consider this if
this thing is say 25 grams of
carbohydrate and that's basically what a
banana is we're talking 100 calories if
you're consuming 2,000 calories a day
this is 5% of your calories a day this
is not gonna make you fat adding a
hundred calories plus the nutrients
minerals all that other stuff there's no
way that's actually causing you to gain
50 pounds you probably have much bigger
issues in terms of 25 grams of
carbohydrate again that's a really small
number actually I suppose if you're
trying to achieve ketosis or something
and you only want 50 grams of carbs a
day hey it sounds like a lot but most
people in 2,000 calories a day are
consuming about half of their calories
from carbohydrate so that's a thousand
calories that's 250 grams a day of carbs
if this is 25 you're talking a tenth of
your calories you could eat in theory 10
of these a day handful of berries a
couple of things no sir no way some
grapes are making you actually fat
another thing people say a lot is honest
the fructose this parts true they say
hey fructose is only stored straight as
fats not processed like glucose and
that's kind of true therefore if I eat
fruit which is full of fructose I'll
then store it all this fat I won't
actually be able to use that energy and
that's complete garbage let me explain
to you one let's take the case of maybe
some blueberries okay so this is a pint
of blueberries two cups is a translation
here right if you were to eat half of
this thing that's about 20 grams of
carbohydrate now no one would ever eat
half of that you're very rare a handful
would be 1/4 or 1/5 of it so you're
talking like five eight ten grams forty
calories 35 calories there's no way it's
enough in that Cup
so imagine half this pint of those 20
grams of carbs about three or four
that's fiber she got to cut that out
immediately and then about three or four
and maybe five our fructose so now we've
really chopped this stuff down 10 grams
of real stuff 5 grams of fiber 5 grams
of fructose of that 5 times of fructose
yes it has to go to the liver in fact
that's the benefit of fruit it actually
replenishes your muscle via liver
glycogen specifically so it's a benefit
post-exercise recovery but although it
has to be processed there the liver can
actually hold like 50 grams in most
servings even of things like this this
25 grams here if it has 5 grams of
fructose you're nowhere near gonna
extend over what the liver can handle
cuz it can handle 50 all right so even
though this has entirely fructose and it
can pretty much has to go to a liver you
got a long you would have to eat ten of
these to exceed the livers capacity to
store fructose and then that fructose
would be started to be stored as
triglycerides so because of all those
reasons the scientific evidence the
fiber the understanding of fructose what
the liver can do with it it's very very
unlikely fruit is making you obese or
overweight alright
go eat your fruit it's delicious
[Music]